<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scientific Computing | My Site</title>
    <link>https://khaled-sammoura.github.io/en/tags/scientific-computing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://khaled-sammoura.github.io/en/tags/scientific-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Scientific Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://khaled-sammoura.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Scientific Computing</title>
      <link>https://khaled-sammoura.github.io/en/tags/scientific-computing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Programming Languages</title>
      <link>https://khaled-sammoura.github.io/en/publication/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://khaled-sammoura.github.io/en/publication/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is a key tool in modern research. It enables process modeling, computational experiments, and the analysis of large datasets. The choice of language depends on the researcher’s objectives as well as the field of application—physics, bioinformatics, engineering, or data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-scientific-programming-languages&#34;&gt;Major Scientific Programming Languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fortran&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One of the oldest languages, still in demand for numerical computations, physical process modeling, and engineering tasks. Known for its high performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C and C++&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Used in fields where execution speed is critical. Suitable for building simulators, scientific computing libraries, and high-performance systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A modern general-purpose language with a wide range of libraries (NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, TensorFlow). Applied in data analysis, machine learning, bioinformatics, and scientific task automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A specialized language for statistics and data analysis. Widely used in social sciences, economics, and biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Julia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A newer language designed for high-performance computing and scientific research. Combines Python’s ease of use with the speed of C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MATLAB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A common tool for engineering calculations, signal processing, and matrix operations. Extensively used in both academia and industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criteria-for-choosing-a-language&#34;&gt;Criteria for Choosing a Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt; — essential for modeling complex systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Library availability&lt;/strong&gt; — determines the ease of solving tasks efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ease of learning&lt;/strong&gt; — affects how quickly students and researchers can adopt it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community support&lt;/strong&gt; — ensures access to documentation and examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming languages form the foundation of computational research. Their effective use accelerates scientific discovery, enables precise modeling, and facilitates the processing of large datasets. In the future, Julia is expected to grow in popularity, while Python will continue expanding into related disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
